Rakshitha Rajanna

ITS Graduate Assistant

St. Louis, MO - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Rakshitha-Rajanna/b46221a6fac5b00c

Highly qualified, talented, tenacious, and well-accomplished professional with 4years+' experience armed with broad-based background and skills as an ITS Graduate Assistant, Business Analyst, Database Administrator, Engineering intern, strategic planning, training, and team building initiatives. I display outstanding ability to plan, coordinate, implement practices, and procedures to bring significant improvements in efficiency, productivity and processes towards the successful attainment of individual and organizational growth. I am determined to implement earned skills and knowledge for the rapid growth of the prospective organization by working effectively and consistently with significant experience in leading and coaching individuals and teams to collaboratively implement operational structures and process that deliver on strategic objectives through good use of communication analysis. AUTHORIZED TO WORK IN USA.

CORE COMPETENCES

- Monitoring project progress and ensuring timely completion.
- Ability to communicate effectively to clarify complex data and sensitive info.
- Thorough understanding of the importance of accurate, detailed reports and plans, with a strong working knowledge of data management.
- · Excellent financial management and budget administration for the maximization of resources and budgets
- Establishing project goals and resolving issues with on-going project.
- Strong motivator/team player with effective and excellent planning, organizational, and negotiation strengths as well as the ability to lead, reach consensus, establish goals, and attain results.
- Ability to facilitate teamwork, builds rapport, manage conflict, and teach, coach, counsel.
- · Highly-effective leadership, organisation effectiveness, culture and change management consulting
- Committed to professional development, willing and able to complete special trainings as required.
- Understanding of change management and implementations of processes within large organizations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ITS Graduate Assistant

Southern New Hampshire University - February 2016 to March 2017

Duties and Responsibilities

- Implemented customized reporting and analysis for a variety of audiences including organizers and management which resulted in improved operational efficiency.
- Worked as a team member to solve problems and complete assignments correctly and efficiently.
- Worked with IT Support Manager and researched alternative approaches to existing software and hardware when standardized approaches could be applied.
- Installed, modified and facilitated the repair of desktop computer hardware and software systems. Diagnosed and corrected system hardware, software and operator problems.
- Provided instructional support Blackboard and technical troubleshooting for Information technology services department. Provided technical assistance and training to system users.
- Monitored solution manager database and servers by using Millennium for retrieving student and patron details by documenting procedures and system changes. Built a website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for University, the project was selected by Universities dining program to serve homeless people. [Outstanding Graduate awarded]

Business Analyst

Reward 360 - Bangalore, Karnataka - May 2015 to November 2015

Duties and Responsibilities

- Provided support to management and other internal customers by performing ad hoc data analysis and worked in special projects of HDFC SmartBuy and all miles reward program.
- Identified and reconcile errors in client data to ensure accurate business requirements.
- Drafted and maintained business requirements and align them with functional and technical requirements.
- Facilitated monthly meetings with clients to document requirements and explore potential solutions.
- Engaged client to gather software requirements/business rules, and ensure alignment with development teams
- Communicated client's business requirements by constructing easy-to-understand data and process models.
- Provided input into developing and modifying systems to meet client needs and develop business specifications to support these modifications.
- Liaised between business and technical personnel to ensure a mutual understanding of processes and applications.

Database Administrator

Measurez - Bangalore, Karnataka - November 2012 to May 2015

Duties and Responsibilities

- Established needs of users and monitoring user access and security for the design and implementation of a database management system; worked for a client construction company and solving user issues and ticketing system.
- Served as DBA in the completion of large-scale implementations, managing projects from business requirements analysis to solutions delivery and support.
- Innovated time-saving, robust employee data-intake system that automated database update functions, enabling customer's queries and process-exception information to be automatically populated with high resolution rate.
- Improved database application performance by monitoring and tuning databases to optimize storage and minimize server processing.
- Dispatched work across team for numerous accounts, providing backup with all aspects of physical / logical design, capacity planning, and performance tuning.
- Enhanced end users' understanding of database systems by conducting pre-implementation workshops, delivering group and individual training sessions and creating user-friendly training materials.
- Successfully lead my team in supporting the Configuration Management, Product Definition, and various other engineering, quality, and manufacturing disciplines, to resolve helpdesk related incidents. Issues associated to resolution of incidents addressed software, data, and customer limitations.

Engineering Intern

NIIT - Bangalore, Karnataka - May 2012 to November 2012

Duties and Responsibilities

- Worked as an intern with team on GPS Software which uses analytics model for IT management and usability testing determining and documenting requirements and formats.
- Provided customer support and engineering through the performance of project engineering and long term local engineering support, on-site installation, as well as troubleshooting and repair of complex equipment and systems.
- Conducted observation and analysis of personnel to determine time and motion requirements of job duties.
- Participated in software development lifecycle, including sprint planning, product demos, and CI and deployment
- Displayed leadership through developing and supervising test procedures
- Worked with Project Managers in the development and revision of work scopes and site specific work plans.

- · Coordinate submittal process, including tracking, reviewing, resubmitting, and monitoring procurement
- Worked with UI/UX team in building a website for consulting company using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Consistently demonstrate company values while seeking to improve through personal and professional development

EDUCATION

MS in Computer & Information Science

Southern New Hampshire University - Manchester, NH 2017

BE in Information Science and Engineering

R.R Institute of Technology - Bangalore, Karnataka 2012

SKILLS

database (3 years), IT Support (1 year), JavaScript (1 year), training (3 years), Business Analysis (3 years), Web Development (2 years), HTML (2 years), Project Management (3 years), Requirements Analysis, SDLC

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Business analysis - UDEMY

May 2017 to Present

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Web Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.
- Database: SQL Server
- Operating systems: Windows XP/7/10, Linux.
- IDE's: Eclipse, Microsoft Project, Visio and Net Beans.
- Functional: Project Management, Business Analysis, Vendor Management, Quality Analysis
- Certified Business Analysis Course on UDEMY (UC-OUUEZCVT).

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Leadership Development

IT Support

Customer Satisfaction

Project Management

Multi - Tasking

Web Development

Quality Assessment

Quality Focus

Creativity

Telephone Etiquette

Business Development

Conflict Resolution

Technical Documentation

Problem Resolution
Policies and Procedure
Quality Assurance
Operations Management
Coaching and Training

TECHNICAL SKILLS Windows and Mac OS Microsoft Office suite

PERSONAL SKILLS
Pro-active
Excellent Communicator
Self-Discipline
Active Listening
Positive Language
Managing Objections

LANGUAGE English